<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Samurai's Blade</name>
    <directory>samurai-blade</directory>
    <id>2925374699</id>
    <description>[h1]A familiar sword wielded by a well-known samurai can now be found in the basement[/h1]
        [h3](Yes, it is Muramasa from Metal Gear Rising: Revengeance, no this is only half a poop-post.)[/h3]

        [i][u]This mod is still in the early stage, it works but there are many synergies missing. There [strike]might also be[/strike] are [b]BUGS[/b]. Also, it is probably severely unbalanced.[/u][/i]


        [i]Quick update (05/03/23): Scaling update is live! Update includes balance changes and a new scaling mechanism! It is still not as feature complete as we'd like, so we'll continue to improve the scaling system. There is also a new mod config menu option to change the position of the new HUD elements.[/i]


        This mod only adds a single item called Samurai's Blade which can be found randomly in boss, treasure and shop rooms [i](Or be picked up at the starting room if you enable that option in the mod config)[/i]. Picking up This item changes Isaac's attack to a unique melee weapon.

        Samurai's Blade has direct and indirect synergies with vanilla and dlc items that does not directly modify tear behavior, so there is a decent amount to discover.

        Although Samurai's Blade has stats of its own, (Swing time, charge-up time, damage, etc.) all of its stats are modified by Isaac's own stats.

        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/p3.gif[/img]


        By default config, item spawns in the starting room. However, this can be changed through mod config menu. The item does appear randomly in treasure, boss and shop item pools.

        Player stats and what they effect:
        [list]
        [*] Damage: Directly modifies damage by a factor of player's damage.
        [*] Fire Delay: Higher fire rate reduces delay between swings.
        [*] Shot speed: Higher shot speed reduces time required for blade to be charged.
        [*] Range, Shot height etc.: Increases blade's arc size.
        [*] Luck : Increases critical hit chance. (For now this is a simple damage increase)
        [/list]


        [h3]Scaling Upgrades[/h3]
        With the latest update, The item gains strength by dealing damage!
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/UpgradeBar.png[/img]

        Each upgrade improves the sword's capabilities by a small amount. Here is a list of upgrades:

        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Attack.png[/img]: Increases attack damage.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Attack-Speed.png[/img]: Increases attack speed.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Boss-Damage.png[/img]: Increases damage dealt against bosses.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Charge-Damage.png[/img]: Increases charged attack damage.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Range.png[/img]: Increases arc size / range.


        Also, do note any and all tear effect-based synergies will work but more complex synergies will not as they need custom implementations, some of which are;
        [list]
        [*] The Ludovico Technique
        [*] Brimstone
        [*] Anything that changes how tears work.
        [/list]



        We have also added a Jetstream Sam costume that gets applied when you pick up the item :)


        [i]Now go be a basement samurai or something, I don't really care.[/i]

        [h3]Known issues[/h3]
        [list]
        [*] Large mirror rooms still cause some visual issues. (I need to figure out a smarter solution, working on it. I hate mirrors.)
        [*] Some enemies have the wrong visual type assigned to them, causing incorrect particles to spawn when they are damaged by the item.
        [*] Tainted Samson's berserk timer does not increase on getting a kill with the item. (Modding API has no non-read-only field for berserk effect cooldown so this might be impossible to fix without doing something custom.)
        [*] Swing sounds are stereo, they should be mono.
        [/list]


        For implementation details and more info here is the [url=https://github.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued]Github link[/url]

        [h3]Credits[/h3]
        [list]
        [*] Base sound effects are from Ultimate Sound FX Bundle.
        [*] Art by Von Duckling.
        [*] Terrible Programming by me.
        [*] Metal Gear series and Metal Gear Rising : Revengeance is owned by Konami Holdings Corporation
        [/list]

    </description>
    <version>0.0.29</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
    <tag id="Sound Effects"/>
</metadata>
