<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Samurai's Blade</name>
    <directory>samurai-blade</directory>
    <id>2925374699</id>
    <description>[h1]A familiar sword wielded by a well-known samurai can now be found in the basement[/h1]
        [h3](Yes, it is Muramasa from Metal Gear Rising: Revengeance, no this is only half a poop-post.)[/h3]

        [i][u]This mod works but many synergies are missing. There [strike]might also be[/strike] are [b]BUGS[/b].[/u][/i]


        [i]Quick update (15/04/23): After reading the comments, I have opted to make the item rarer. Item no longer spawns in treasure and shop rooms, the chance to appear in boss room is reduced and item now appears in other 'rarer' pools such as secret, ultra-secret, etc. I am willing to take feedback on this change and adjust it accordingly.[/i]


        This mod only adds a single item called Samurai's Blade which can be found randomly in different item pools[i](Or be picked up at the starting room if you enable that option in the mod config)[/i]. Picking up This item changes Isaac's attack to a unique melee weapon.

        Samurai's Blade has direct and indirect synergies with vanilla and dlc items that does not directly modify tear behavior, so there is a decent amount to discover.

        Although Samurai's Blade has stats of its own, (Swing time, charge-up time, damage, etc.) all of its stats are modified by Isaac's own stats.

        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/p3.gif[/img]


        Player stats and what they effect:
        [list]
        [*] Damage: Directly modifies damage by a factor of player's damage.
        [*] Fire Delay: Higher fire rate reduces delay between swings.
        [*] Shot speed: Higher shot speed reduces time required for blade to be charged.
        [*] Range, Shot height etc.: Increases blade's arc size.
        [*] Luck : Increases critical hit chance. (For now this is a simple damage increase)
        [/list]


        [h3]Scaling Upgrades[/h3]
        With the latest update, The item gains strength by dealing damage!
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/UpgradeBar.png[/img]

        Each upgrade improves the sword's capabilities by a small amount, permanently. Here is a list of upgrades:

        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Attack.png[/img]: Increases attack damage.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Attack-Speed.png[/img]: Increases attack speed.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Boss-Damage.png[/img]: Increases damage dealt against bosses.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Charge-Damage.png[/img]: Increases charged attack damage.
        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/Upgrade-Range.png[/img]: Increases arc size / range.

        These incremental upgrades are very small, but adds up quickly, making the item much stronger as you deal damage with it!


        Also, do note any and all tear effect-based synergies will work but more complex synergies will not as they need custom implementations, some of which are;
        [list]
        [*] The Ludovico Technique
        [*] Brimstone
        [*] Anything that changes how tears work.
        [/list]


        [b]I strongly recommend you to get the Mod Config Menu either [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2681875787&searchtext=Mod+Config+Menu] Pure[/url] or the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2487535818&searchtext=Mod+Config+Menu]continued [/url] version. There are many options to customize the blade's behavior to your liking.[/b]



        We have also added a Jetstream Sam costume that gets applied when you pick up the item :)


        [i]Now go be a basement samurai or something, I don't really care.[/i]

        [h3]Known issues[/h3]
        [list]
        [*] Scaling stats don't carry over sessions. If you close the game and reopen it, the scaling stats are reset.
        [*] Large mirror rooms still cause some visual issues. (This is happening because I abused the Sprite rendering in a way I shouldn't have. Unfortunately, a proper fix to this issue would require me to rewrite a large part of the code.)
        [*] Some enemies have the wrong visual type assigned to them, causing incorrect particles to spawn when they are damaged by the item. (Fixed most of them, let me know if you find more.)
        [*] Tainted Samson's berserk timer does not increase on getting a kill with the item. (Modding API has no non-read-only field for berserk effect cooldown so this might be impossible to fix without doing something custom.)
        [*] Swing sounds are stereo, they should be mono. (Not a real issue.)
        [/list]


        For implementation details and more info here is the [url=https://github.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued]Github link[/url]

        [h3]Credits[/h3]
        [list]
        [*] Base sound effects are from Ultimate Sound FX Bundle.
        [*] Art by Von Duckling.
        [*] Terrible Programming by me.
        [*] Metal Gear series and Metal Gear Rising : Revengeance is owned by Konami Holdings Corporation
        [/list]

    </description>
    <version>0.0.30</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Graphics"/>
    <tag id="Sound Effects"/>
</metadata>
