<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Samurai's Blade</name>
    <directory>samurai-blade</directory>
    <id>2925374699</id>
    <description>
        [h1]A familiar sword from a well-known samurai can now be found in the basement[/h1]
        [h3](Yes, it is Muramasa from Metal Gear Rising, no this is only half a poop-post.)[/h3]

        [i][u]This mod is still in the early stage, it works but there are many synergies missing. There might also be [b]BUGS[/b]. Also  it is probably severely unbalanced.[/u][/i]


        This mod only adds a single item called Samurai's Blade which can be found as a boss drop [i](Or be picked up at the starting room if you enable that option in the mod config)[/i]. Picking up This item changes Isaac's attack to a unique melee weapon.

        Samurai's Blade has direct and indirect synergies with most vanilla and dlc items, so there is a lot to discover.

        Although Samurai's Blade has stats of its own, (Swing time, charge-up time, damage, etc.) all of its stats are modified by Isaac's own stats.

        [img]https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued/main/media/p2.gif[/img]


        By default config, item spawns in the starting room. However, this can be changed through mod config menu. The item does appear randomly in treasure, boss and shop item pools.

        Player stats and what they effect:
        [list]
        [*] Damage: Directly modifies damage by a factor of player's damage.
        [*] Fire Delay: Higher fire rate reduces delay between swings.
        [*] Shot speed: Higher shot speed reduces time required for blade to be charged.
        [*] Range, Shot height etc.: Increases blade's arc size.
        [*] Luck : Increases critical hit chance. (For now this is a simple damage increase)
        [/list]


        Also do note any and all tear effect-based synergies will work but more complex synergies will not as they need custom implementations, some of which are;
        [list]
        [*] The Ludovico Technique
        [*] Brimstone
        [*] Anything that changes how tears work.
        [/list]

        If you have the mod config menu mod, you can also modify item stats (currently only damage).

        Now go be a basement samurai or something, I don't really care.



        Github Link: https://github.com/Math-Man/samurai-blade-continued

        Credits:
        [list]
        [*] Base sound effects are from Ultimate Sound FX Bundle.
        [*] Art by Von Duckling.
        [*] Terrible Programming by me.
        [*] Metal Gear series and Metal Gear Rising owned by Konami Holdings Corporation
        [/list]
    </description>
    <version>0.0.11</version>
    <visibility>Private</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
</metadata>
